[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa automation tutorial as you
all know I already published 36 YouTube
videos in terms of overall tricentis
Concepts and I've published 21 YouTube
videos in terms of advanced level
Concepts
this is our lesson 37 in terms of prent
tasa automation Concepts and this is our
lesson 22 in terms of advanced level
Concepts in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can you perform drag and
drop operations by using
trioscope we are going to take one OB
cycle where we need to drag some of the
records from your first web table and
drop them into your second web table I'm
going to use repetition method while
performing drag and drop
operations during web application
automation so in this lesson what we are
going to do we are going to
perform drag and drop operation by using
two web tables the first one is you have
first web table called to-do tasks and
then you have another web table called
completed
tasks and we going to drag and drop all
the tasks from to-do table to completed
task
table and while doing this we're going
to use drag and drop operations also
repetition property at folder level to
achieve
this and following is the URL that we we
are going to use to perform this
particular
automation let us first understand what
is the challenge that we have or what is
the obstacle that we have and then how
can we automate this particular
challenge by using tric andsa if you see
on the screen this is your to-do task
this is one web table and this is your
completed task this is another web table
so let us assume I completed my task one
with the ID 1 so I need to drag and drop
into completed task RP table and I need
to drag the second task onto
completed tasks I need to drag third
task onto completed task so this way I
need to drag and drop all the rows of
to-do tasks to the completed task so how
I'm dragging and dropping I'm dragging
and dropping in the order of sequence ID
sequence 1 2 3 4 5 6 right that's what
I'm going to perform so now how can you
do this particular scenario how can you
perform this particular scenario by
using triena so let us go to trient tosa
what I'm going to do here first I want
to create a new module so for that let
me scan the module okay let's go to
modules right click scan the
application
so this this is the application that I
would like to scan Okay click on
scan and here if you see these two are
the tables to- do task is one table
let's highlight this
okay yes this is the one and the other
one is completed tasks this is another
web table see it is highlighting so that
means these two are the tables and I'm
going to name this module as obstacle
okay copy this and name this
module as
obstacle whatever the abst number and
now so here I would like to make small
change to the completed tasks what I'm
going to do I'm going to take the
property called class name instead of ID
I'm going to take property called out
Outer text and then I'll just make sure
that I'll remove all these I'm going to
introduce regular expression ID task
assign these are the columns and then
whatever it might be so if you enter the
table uh data then you will have lot of
text after assigning I'm just
introducing a regular expression okay
and now
oh let me see I think it is not uniquely
identifying that's okay not a problem
okay so now let me save this particular
test case so before save let me make
sure one more time okay
tasks table
assigning yeah make it unique what we'll
do is making unique by
using okay uh by using default name that
it's okay let's keep this okay now save
this so as soon as I save
it so this will be saved as a new module
in trient to so this is what we saved
just now right so now I want to create a
new folder here in the exercise let me
create a new folder called drag and
drop
drag and
drop and here I'll create a new test
case called dragdrop
operations
now let me drag this particular module
to my test
case here what I'm going to do what is
the column that we are actually dragging
we are using the column called ID so
that's why I'm going to select the
column ID
here
and before I do this right I need to use
the repetition why because I need to
drag the rows in the sequence of ID 1 2
3 4 these are all not not in sequence so
these are all actually randomly placed
right so for that what I'm going to do
I'm going to create one folder here
under this test case
I'll create one folder right click and
then create one folder called repetition
sorry I created
something contrl
Zed right click and
create create a folder right click and
create a folder I'm going to name this
as repetition okay now I want to drag
and drop this entire test case into
repetition folder so if you see
here under repetition so I'm just moving
the module aside so that you can see how
can I define the repetition folder okay
I want to Define this folder
repetition as six because I have six
rows to drag and drop I'm going to
define the repetition property for this
folder as
six okay now here as I told you I select
the column
ID
and I need
to
drag one now so instead of dragging one
I want to use the
repetion property copy
this and here open curly braces
repetition Clos curly the cell value
what happens first it comes as one
now I want to
drag close curly
braces and here it is input instead of
verify so what I'm doing here for the
first time it comes as
one
and under repetition and then I'm
dragging that particular cell okay under
column ID that is done and and now I
want to drop onto this table correct now
I want to Simply drop I don't want to
consider any row here I just need to
drop onto the table that's why I'm going
to Simply use drop method
drop open curly braces and close curly
braces right so now let us understand
one more time what I'm doing here first
I selected the column ID
and that
column what is the cell that I want to
select first I want to select one that's
why I'm using the repetition method here
starts with one and it ends with six so
the same I'm calling here repetition and
I'm dragging that row and then I'm
dropping on to
table right so now let us run the test
case and see if tasa can drag and drop
all these rows to the completed tasks
okay let me right click and
run we will debug if we have any issues
okay so it should pick up the last row
because the repetition comes as
one it pick up the r row but somehow it
is not dropping into completed
let's see what is the
failure here the failure
says the failure
says could not
complete could not find table it says
could not find table okay let's see here
miss okay so basically one thing here
what we are one mistake is here I'm
actually selecting I'm not selecting as
input here so let me select as input and
try one more time okay let's try this
one more time okay so now right click
and run in
scratchbook let me now it should pick up
one the last row and drop into completed
tasks yes it is dropping and it should
pick up two because the repetition
folder sends repetition value as two and
then three and then four right so it is
dragging and dropping all the rows from
to-do tasks to the completed
tasks so our obstacle is successful so
we solve the automation problem by using
Tsar so what we are doing here we are
actually dragging and dropping all all
the rows from one web table to the
another web table by using repetition
operation so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your
queries hope you all understand how can
you perform drag and drop operations
while automating your web
application by using trient to and also
know now how can you use the repetion
method trien Taska please do subscribe
to the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever iish more
videos thank
[Music]
you